SYED ATIF AHMED

+92 322 2861659 | satifoverip@hotmail.com Linkedin | Facebook | YouTube

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Sr. Technical Consultant on Linux, VMware and Microsoft Technologies and Cybersecurity Professional on LAN, EPN, WAN and WLAN Networks with a strong interest in cybersecurity, exploitation, penetration testing, vulnerability analysis, system and network security. Offering 12+ years of managerial and technical background on Linux, VMware and Microsoft Solutions. Specializing in domestic and global deployments of Linux Infrastructure and Microsoft Products. I have designed and implemented Server's Infrastructure Projects throughout Oman, Middle East and West African Regions and have a real-world solution experience with some of the largest enterprises. I have used several Linux Distributions on my variety of projects including Linux Mint, Debian, Ubuntu, Kali Linux, MX Linux, CentOS, Fedora and Others. I also enjoy teaching others and share my knowledge about how to use and exploit the power of Linux Operating System and apply those core Linux skills to break into Systems and Networks. Currently in a cybersecurity role where I continue to develop and learn new abilities while contributing to the overall success of the organization. I also possess:

- Experience in scripting languages including Bash and Python
- Experience with security toolkits such as Kali Linux, Parrot Security, Metasploit, Nessus and Burp Suite.
- Proficient in Ethical Hacking, Exploitations, Penetration Testing, Virtualization, Systems Administration, Vagrant, Ansible and SCCM
- Proficient in Web Development Projects
- Passionate in learning new open-source products
- Ability to handle multiple projects simultaneously
- Applies good expertise and initiatives in carrying out assigned tasks
- Have a nack for getting the job done on schedule

EDUCATION

Sir Syed University of Engineering and Technology

BS, Computer System Engineering

D.J Sindh Govt Science College

FSC (Pre-Engineering)

CERTIFICATIONS

- Introduction to Linux
- MCSE
- MCP
- MCTS
- Microsoft Specialist (Configuring Windows Devices)
- A+

COURSES

- Ethical Hacking from Scratch
- Complete Penetration Testing and Ethical Hacking Bootcamp
- Certified Ethical Hacker (CEH v9)
- Pentest+
- Security+
- Practical Ethical Hacking The Complete Course
- Python & Ethical Hacking from Scratch
- Diploma in Information Technology
- CCNA
- Introduction to Linux
- Linux Administration
- Linux Shell Scripting: A Project-Based Approach
- Linux Projects
- The Complete 2020 Web Development Bootcamp
- MCSE Server Infrastructure
- MCTS (Business Desktop Deployment)
- Private Cloud
- Microsoft Azure
- Amazon Web Services

EXPERIENCE

LyncSoft Services, Remote/Sydney, Australia Founder / Penetration Tester / Cyber Security Consultant

July 2018 to Present

- Engage in a variety of penetration testing assessments including network (internal and external), web application, wireless, red and blue team, physical, social engineering.
- Conducted penetration tests against virtualized live systems to determine current system/network vulnerabilities and apply appropriate patching.
- Performed as a Linux system administrator (Red Hat/CentOS, Ubuntu, Linux Mint)
- Planning and Deployment of LAMP Servers.
- Performed Installation, Migrations and Upgradation of Linux Mint and Ubuntu Flavor's

Microsoft Nov 2016 to June 2018

Sr. Technical Consultant / Partner Seller (Enterprise Mobility + Security)

- Drive a strong co-sell motion with Microsoft
- Access to exclusive content and deep engagement with Microsoft teams
- Partner Seller Meetups and Conferences
- Access to the Microsoft Corporate Network
- Involved in deployment and training on Operation Management Suite and Azure Site Recovery
- Conducted Showcase Technical Demonstration and POC's to Prospective clients.
- Interact with clients on high and technical levels to discuss findings and resolutions.
- Unique access to Microsoft Full Time Employee (FTE) enablement and the Microsoft-endorsed Partner Seller credential.
- Responsible for detailed Plan, Design and Implementation of System Center Solutions for prospective clients as well as provide cloud-based solution on Microsoft Azure Platform such as EMS, OMS, Azure Site Recovery and Azure Backup.

KalSoft Limited May 2006 to Feb 2009

Sr. IS Consultant / Infrastructure Engineer

- Involved in the designing and implementation of AD, Exchange, System Center Configuration Management solutions.
- Responsible for all the problems resolutions pertaining to ongoing projects.
- Handled all escalations related to the IT Projects.
- Provided pre sales and technical support for regional and middle-east customers.
- Meetings with prospective customers to discuss the viability and feasibility of the proposed solution and upcoming opportunities.
- SCCM deployment and migration projects from ranging several 100 to over 25,000 users

OMAN (MUSCAT) EXPERIENCE

Microsoft Consultant, MHD Infotech LLC

Sep 2012 to Aug 2013

- Migration from SCCM 2007 R3 to SCCM 2012 SP1 Infrastructure
- Deployment of SCCM 2012 SP1 With System Center Endpoint Protection
- Envisioning, Planning, Deployment & Training of SCCM 2007 R3 & SCOM 2007 R2 to Daleel's Petroleum LLC IT Staff.
- Envisioning, Planning, Deployment of Microsoft Forefront End Point Protection and Integrate with SCCM 2007 R3 at Majan Electricity.
- Envisioning, Planning, Deployment, Migration of SCCM 2007 R3 to SCCM 2012 & Training of System Center Configuration Manager 2012 to HCT Muscat IT Staff.

Technical Consultant, International Office Products

April 2012 to Aug 2012

- Responsible for the Designing, Planning and Implementation of Microsoft System Center 2012.
- Envisioning, Planning, Deployment of Microsoft System Center Operation Manager.

System Engineer (PERN II),

Higher Education Commission

- Responsible of Managing and Maintaining of AD and SCCM 2007 R2 Infrastructure.
- Involved in System Center Configuration Manager 2007 R2

PROJECTS

LyncSoft Services

Oct 2019 to May 2020

Sep 2009 to Sep 2010

Cyber Security Consultant

- Smart Office Network Infrastructure Implementation
- Kali Linux Migrations and Distribution Upgradation
- Parrot Security OS Deployment
- Penetration Testing Virtual Lab Deployment Using VMWare
- CentOS Migration from Centos 7.7 to CentOS 8.1
- Vagrant and Oracle Virtual Box 6.0 Deployment on CentOS 8.1
- TunnelBear VPN Client Configuration and Setup on Windows 10, Ubuntu, Kali Linux and Android Devices
- Penetration Testing and Exploitation of different operating systems such as Windows XP, Windows 7, Windows 8.1, Windows 10, Windows Server 2008R2, Windows Server 2012R2, Windows Server 2016, Windows Server 2019, Metasploitable 2.0 Linux and Red Hat Enterprise 7 and more.

United Kingdom

Cross Platforms Implementation Using Samba & SSH Server Infrastructure on Debian GNU Linux

LyncSoft Services

Cyber Security Researcher/Technical Consultant

- Linux Mint Migration and Systems Upgradation from 17.2 to 19.2
- Wireless Penetration Testing WPA/WPA2 Networks
- Barqiat برقبات (A Project of LyncSoft) is an Online Store which provides electronics products and all kind of accessories for electronic devices & smartphones.

IOP (Pvt) Limited

- Deployment of Microsoft Advance Threat Analytics.
- Microsoft Advanced Threat Analytics is an on-premises platform that helps protect your enterprise from multiple types of advanced targeted cyber-attacks and insider threats.
- SIEM Integration
- Windows Event Forwarding (WEF)
- Directly from the Windows Event Collector (for the Lightweight Gateway)

Confiz Limited Data Center (Lahore)

- Designing, Planning and Deployment of System Center Configuration Manager
- Patch Management Using SCCM and WSUS
- Softwares Delivery and Distribution

Marie Stopes International

Dec 2016 to Jan 2017

- Microsoft Azure POC
- Site to Site Virtual Private Network
- Windows Server 2016 Deployment on Azure
- SharePoint Server Deployment on Azure

Qatar Ministries (Doha)

July 2008 to Aug 2008

- Submitted a proposal of Business Desktop for 40,000 Desktops for migration in Qatar Ministries.
- Provided Business Desktop Deployment recommendation for 24 affiliates for successful BDD Deployment
- using Zero touch deployment.

MTN Nigeria (Lagos)

Feb 2008

- Worked as Technical Lead for Microsoft focused consulting practice with a focus on Business Desktop Deployment, Active Directory Services, and SMS 2003 for MTN Nigeria.
- Automated Deployment of Vista Enterprise with Office 2007 on Bare Metal and Refresh Scenarios.

Deputy Commissioner Office Islamabad (CDCO)

Infrastructure Services Consultant

- Design and Deployment of Windows Server 2003 Clustering
- Deployment of SQL Server 2005 With Failover Cluster
- Design & Implementation of LCS 2005 Infrastructure
- Design & Implementation of Network Load Balancing

Ministry of Foreign Affairs (Islamabad)

Aug 2007

- Deployment of Windows Server Infrastructure
- Design & Implement Active Directory Infrastructure
- Plan, Design & Implement ISA Server 2006 Infrastructure

KKI, Phase I & II

Nov 2006 to April 2007

Nov 2007 to Jan 2008

Associate IS Consultant

- Design and Implementing Windows Server Infrastructure
- Design & Implement Active Directory Infrastructure
- Design & Implement Exchange 2003 Infrastructure
- Deployment of LCS 2005
- Failover Cluster for SQL Server 2000
- NLB Cluster for Remitton Web Application

Election Commission of Pakistan

Mar 2005 to Dec 2005

Electrol Unit Management System & Wireless LAN

- Designing and Implementing Electrol Unit Management System using VB.Net and MS SQL Server.
- Installation and Configuration of different Servers, Interfaces and Implementing Security Policies.
- Designing and Implementing Wireless LAN Solution.

CAPACITY BUILDING

YouTube, Lync Academy Online

December 2015 to Present

Trainer, Content Creator

Currently the trainer for the Linux, Ethical Hacking and Penetration Testing Course.

Actively post cybersecurity training videos on YouTube and Facebook.

LyncSoft Services

Conducted Ethical Hacking Bootcamp

Tools and Technologies

Kali Linux, Metasploitable-2 Linux, Nessus, Burp Suite, Metasploit, VMWare, Windows 10,

Windows 7, Windows XP

Pearl Continental Khi April 2018

Presented Microsoft M365 Security and Compliance Workshop

Microsoft Intune and Live Demos on MDM, MAM WE and Conditional Access Policies

Tools and Technologies

Intune, Azure, SCCM

Nov 2017 Pearl Continental Khi

Presented Azure Site Recovery Live Showcase Demo

Failover and Failback of Hyper V Linux Server on Microsoft Azure Site Recovery

Tools and Technologies

Linux, Hyper-V, Azure

Dec 2017 **Onwire Technology**

Conducted Two Days Bootcamp on Planning and Deployment of SCCM

Current Branch 1606

Tools and Technologies

Hyper-V, SCCM, Intune

Oct 2018

Mövenpick Karachi October 2019

Presented OMS and Advance Threat Analytics

Tools and Technologies

Hyper-V, Azure, OMS

NED University of Engineering & Technology Oct 2017

Conducted Microsoft Windows 10 Bootcamp

Tools and Technologies

Windows 10, Hyper-V

CTTC (Pvt) Limited Feb 2016

MCSE Server Infrastructure Training

Tools and Technologies

Hyper V, Windows Server 2016

Pakistan Air Force SCCM Corporate Training

Islamabad Aug 2013

Train Pakistan Air Force Infrastructure Pool on Administering and Deploying

System Center 2012 Configuration Manager

Tools and Technologies

Windows 7, SCCM, Hyper V

Higher Education Commission Islamabad July 2010

Hosted a Workshop on SCCM for "Capacity Building of IT Staff" in HEC

Head Office (Islamabad) published including in the HEC News & Views Magazine

Tools and Technologies

Windows 7, SCCM

Ministry of Education Oman (Muscat)

June 2008

Conducting a Workshop, Training & Deployment of MDT 2008 using Lite Touch Scenario.

Tools and Technologies

Windows Vista, MDT 2008

KalSoft Lahore Office Training

Dec 2007

Provide Customize Hands-On Training on Live Communication Server 2005 to Infrastructure Support Team.

Tools and Technologies

LCS 2005, Virtual PC